本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
パルス暦３２１年
The era of Parsis, 321 a year.
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
アルスラーンはパルスの居城となった
Arslan went to the main castle Parsis,
Fortress Peshavard their strongholds in the north.
北の要塞ペシャワール城へ向かっていた
And he returned back with a new companion, Jaswant.
それは　新たな同士ジャスワントを迎えての帰還であった
kaze ga zawameki kudaketa kimochi
Quiet wind awakens emotions and broken,
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
misukashi teru you de furueta yo
I see through everything and I shiver.
michita tsuki no hi touboe no inochi
In the sky a full moon, and the city comes howling:
片源
Rei
时间轴
钦钦&雪糕
压制
Coolkid
mada oite kanaide yo
"Please do not throw until we have!"
bokura torikaeseru ka na iro tsuki no sora
Will we return to the old sky, painted in the colors?
hokori mamire no yume mai agete
Rise in the dance vortex hourglass Sci,
kobushi wo nigittanara
to be clamped in their fists.
ima hashire hashire tsuji kaze ni natte
Now run forward, run forward, and stand by the whirlwind,
rettou zetsubou issai fukitobashite iku
feelings of hopelessness and despair of sour cream on the way.
oikakenakya saigo no tobira
Clears the currently last track.
nando chittatte dai gyakuten
Let all break, we will rise again,
kono goe ga shagare tatte inorinouta todoketai yo
even a hoarse voice will sing songs and prayers.
tarinai bokura de shinji teta sekai wo ubaetara
Even insignificant, as we will be able to capture the whole world in which to believe.
madamada madamada make rarenai
We have still not yet been defeated!
Chapter XIX
You are asking me to take the castle Zabul?
ザーブル城を攻略せよと仰せか
Yes.
ああ
by deceit
わざわざ策を弄し　ボダンと聖騎士団を追い出したまではよかったが
lure Baudin and the temple knights. This is the best variant.
ヤツらにザーブル城を占拠され　本国との連絡にも事を欠く始末
Now they occupied the castle of Zabul,
and it is difficult to even communicate with their homeland.
This idiot has recently put forward a serious claim.
そのうえ　ヤツめ…せんだって　いくつかの要求を突きつけてきた
Brother of the king of the kingdom Lyusitaniya, the grand vizier and supreme commander of the army, Giscard
What are the requirements?
どのようなものです？
アンドラゴラスとタハミーネの処刑だ
Execute Andragorasa and Tahameney.
Besides,
更に　異教徒の女にうつつを抜かした兄上に対しては
from my brother, bound to a Gentile,
神への懺悔と一生戒律を破らないと新たに誓約せよと
It requires repentance before God
and a new oath not to betray their faith while he was still alive.
This Bodine! ..
ボダンめ　神の名を借りて教会の権力を増大させようとしている
It uses the name of the Lord to increase the power of the church.
And thirty thousand people in the castle of Zabul one can not take seriously.
ザーブル城にいる３万も侮れぬ
彼らはボダンの命であれば　火の中に入るのもいとわぬ者ばかりだ
If Bodin requires it,
therefore, each of them is ready to go through fire and water.
General wage kingdom Lyusitaniya, Mr. Silver mask, Hermes
Take this job, Prince.
お引き受けなさいませ　殿下
But, Saam, Giscard's intentions are obvious.
だが　サーム　ギスカールの本心は知れている
Sending us against the Knights of the Temple,
俺たちを聖騎士団とかませ　共倒れすればよいと思っている
he hopes that we will kill each other.
But, thanks to this retaliatory mission
ですが　討伐という名の下に　殿下は兵を集めることができます
you will be able to raise an army.
Then, using the treasury Lyusitanii miserable,
ルシタニアどもの費用を使って
to gain full army and equip it.
兵士と武器を調えることができるではございませんか
Clear. This is logical.
なるほど　一理あるな
In addition, we have opposed to the Temple Knights
それに　対立している聖騎士団は
Mr. Counselor silver mask, Saam
fanatics, the heaviest lyusitaintsev.
ルシタニア人の中でも始末の悪い狂信者です
If we are able to destroy them,
彼らを討ち滅ぼすことができれば
for most people it will also be Parsis welcome development.
パルスの民にとっては誠に歓迎すべきこと
Because you will be one day rule over them,
殿下はいずれパルス人の上に君臨なさる御身なれば
it clearly will not be superfluous.
決して損にはなりますまい
Here's how you think.
それがサームの考えか
But what if you are defeated?
だが　負けたらどうする
英雄王カイ・ホスローのご子孫ともあるお方が
A descendant of the king-hero Kayhosrova
says the word "defeat"?
負けるという言葉を口にするとは…
Without winning the Bodine will be no recovery Parsis.
ボダンを倒せずして　パルスの復興はありえませんぞ
Do not say such oddities.
情けないことをおっしゃいますな
Yes you are right.
確かにそのとおりだ　よく助言してくれたな
You make a good adviser.
I polschen.
恐れ入ります
I'm glad I took you into his service again.
やはり　お前を俺の臣下に迎えてよかった
サームよ　やはり城門を開いて　打って出るべきだ
Saam, I think we should open the gates and attack.
What else do we cavalry?
なんのための騎兵だ
焦るな
Calmer.
Arise, slaves!
立ち上がれ　奴隷たち
お前たちを縛り　搾取するパルスに
How long will you bow to the Pars,
which fettered and uses you ?!
いつまで頭を垂れているのか
Garshasf! Are you bursting with pride for the murder of a slave ?!
ガルシャースフ　奴隷を殺して自慢になるのか
This is not a slave, and the rebels!
ヤツらは奴隷ではない　謀反人だ
In whose hands one stick ?!
棒切れしか持たぬ者をか
And in the soul their swords!
心に剣を持っておったわ
こいつら　どこから
Where are those bastards ?!
くそ　地下水路からか
Heck! They go from underground channels ?!
How?!
どうして
なっ　カーラーン
Harlan!
カーラーン　寝返ったとの話は本当だったのか
Harlan! So it's true that you over to the enemy ?!
なぜ　国を売った
Why did you betray the kingdom ?!
So the circumstances! You do not understand!
故あってのことよ　お主には分からぬ
おお　当たり前だ　分かるものか
Oh sure! I'll never understand!
K ... who are you ... that ...
な…何者…
Legitimate member of the royal family ...
正統な王家の血筋
up to you, believe it or not.
信じるか信じないかは自由だ
Then I threw the spear at you with intent to kill.
あのとき　俺はお前を殺すつもりで槍を放った
But now you're here and alive.
だが　今　お前はこうして生きている
You once nearly lost his life. Now, entrust it to me.
一度は失いかけた命を俺に預けろ
お前しだいだ
You will decide.
自分の目と耳で　確かめざるをえない
I had to trust my own eyes and ears.
何人もこの中に入ることはかなわぬ
Nobody is allowed to enter!
Eighteenth kingdom pars ruler Andragoras III
サームか
Yield.
It is true, Your Majesty.
さようでございます　陛下
Why did you come?
何をしに来た
I'm here because I have something to ask you, Your Majesty.
陛下に伺いたいことがあり　参上いたしました
What to ask?
何を聞きたい
About what happened seventeen years ago.
１７年前の一件でございます
陛下　あえて伺います
Your Majesty, I daresay ...
Seventeen years ago, you killed, His Majesty, King Osroesa?
１７年前　陛下はオスロエス王を暗殺なさったのですか
Killed the brother of the king, to take the throne in his stead?
兄王を殺害して　王位を奪われたのですか
And then tried to burn alive Prince Hermes?
そして　ヒルメス王子を焼き殺そうとなさったのですか
What sense now to ask about this?
今更　それを聞いてどうする
I am a person who does not stand out outstanding talent.
私は戦う以外に能のない男です
But by the grace of the royal family
それが王家の恩寵を頂き
I gave a great position marzban.
マルズバーンなどという名誉ある地位にしていただけました
I am indebted to the royal family,
私は王家に恩があり　また　このパルスという国に愛着がございます
and I love my country Pars.
So I want you to dispel all my illusions and delusions.
故に　私の迷妄を陛下に覚ましていただきたいと思い
That's what worries me.
伺ったしだいです
That's it.
そんなことか
If you ask me about it, so willing to endure a cruel hell?
お前は地獄の深淵に立つ覚悟があって　わしに問うておるのか
Your Majesty ...
陛下…
I just followed the prediction.
わしは予言に従ったまでだ
Since ancient times, the history of the royal family Parsis
とうの昔から　パルス王家の歴史は血とうそで塗り固められておるのだ
It was soaked with blood and lies.
だが…　それをお前ごときが知ってどうする
But...
The help that knowledge such as you?
Time.
時間だ
It is clear, so you agree.
そうか　受けてくれるか
無論　武器と食料は十分にそろえていただきます
Of course.
I hope that the weapons and supplies will be available in the right quantity.
And again, because you can not afford to spare any of Lyusitanii army
それと
ルシタニア正規軍の兵力を割いていただくわけにはいきませぬゆえ
I would like to raise an army of Parsis.
こちらでパルス人の兵士を集めさせていただきたい
Good. I trust it to you.
よかろう　お主に任せる
Then...
では
Your Highness, whether to go on about the Gentiles?
王弟殿下　異教徒を使ってもよいものでしょうか
ヤツらの矛先がいつ　こちらへ向かってくるとも分かりませぬぞ
It is unknown at what point they will direct their spears against us.
I know.
分かっておる
Silver mask ...
銀仮面め…　どうせヤツもよからぬ目算があるに違いないが
No doubt he also plotting something awful,
but so far
さしあたり
ザーブル城に立てこもる阿呆どもと戦ってくれるというのだ
He agreed for us to fight with fools, barricaded in the castle of Zabul.
Battle cause damage to him.
戦えば損害も受けよう
This castle seems invulnerable,
あの城は難攻不落に見えますが　実はいくつかの弱点があります
but in fact there are a few weak points.
I was in the castle somewhere in two or three times,
私は三度ほどあの城に赴き　内部をよく調べております
and examined it from the inside.
In any case, there is no reason
いずれにせよ　あやつらのために無理をなさる必要はございますまい
overstrained because these reptiles.
We will require as much time as it takes to cook.
十分に時間をかけ　準備を整えなさいませ
Yes. I do not intend to lose in this game.
ああ　この戦　負けるわけにはいかぬ
The time will come when I turn out of our borders lyusitaniantsev
いずれ俺はルシタニア人を国外にたたき出し
and ascend to the throne of the royal capital.
王都で国王として即位する
Yes.
はい
And after that deprive animals Adragorasa and Arslan
そのうえで　アンドラゴラスとアルスラーンの首をはね
and post them on the gates of the castle.
城門にさらしてくれよう
of March
３月１日
Punitive expedition to the castle Zabul, led by Hermes
ヒルメスが率いるザーブル城討伐隊はパルス人のみで結成された
It was collected from parsiantsev.
I did not expect that Hermes will bring together more than thirty thousand people ...
まさか　３万を超える兵がヒルメスのもとに集まるとは…
We'll see how many come back after the fight.
戦の後　戻る者がどれほどか…
People deprived of the title of Knights of the Temple,
聖騎士団を追放になった者が山賊に身をやつし
posing as gangsters and repairing robberies in these areas?
この辺りで暴れていたのか
Yes. They destroy everything.
へえ　そりゃもうひどいありさまで
And a traveler alone strayed from these bandits?
その山賊を旅人がたった１人で撃退したというのだな
Yes.
へえ　本人が言うには　なんでも自分は相当偉い人物で
People says,
that he had esteemed rank
and is a few tens of thousands of people.
何万人もの部下を従えていたとか
This man is so strong?
その男　本当に強かったのか
Silenus? You could say that ...
強いのなんのって　１人で１５人ほどを倒しちまいましてね
After all, he alone killed fifteen people.
What was he like?
どんな男だった
How? ..
どんなって…
Well, the one-eyed thug who loves wine and women.
酒と女が大好きな　片目の大男ですがね
Clear. Sorry to have kept you.
分かった　引き止めて悪かったな
Yes.
Prince, I have guesses about whom they had just said,
殿下　今の話の男について　私に心当たりがございますゆえ
so I'll go to him.
会うてまいります
If it will be your ally, it will be useful.
殿下の味方になれば　頼もしいかぎりでございます
もうたつことにした　謝礼の酒と女ならいらんぞ
I've thought to leave.
If the wine or women as a sign of gratitude, you do not need.
久しぶりだな
Long time no see,
kingdom cavalry captain Parsa, Kubard
クバード
Kuʙard.
サームか
Yield?
半年ぶりだ　元気そうだな
Half a year has passed. I see you're still alive.
おお
Yes.
お前が生きているとは　正直思わなんだ
To be honest, I do not expect you to survive.
The royal capital still have survived?
王都には　まだ生き残っている者がおるのか
生き恥をさらしているのは俺だけだ
Just a shame I survived.
Can you humiliate yourself,
お前が自分を卑下するのは勝手だが
俺は別に生き恥をさらしているという気はないぞ
but it is unlikely I do not live without shame.
今　命があればこそ　酒も飲めるし　女も抱ける
Because I'm alive,
the wine and drink away so women take it.
気に入らないルシタニアの阿呆どももぶった斬ることができるのだからな
I can also slightly beat these idiots from Lyusitanii.
出立の準備か
You're going to leave?
ああ
Yes.
酒と女欲しさに村を救ったのだが
I helped the village, because they do not have enough wine and women,
女たちが俺の嫁の座を狙って争いを始めた
but the girls have already begun to fight, who will be my bride.
うれしい悩みではないか
I wish I had these problems.
どこがだ
Yes, of course.
くだらん争いなど　犬も食わん
Even the dog did not get into this kind of life.
俺はそれがいちばん煩わしい
this is the most tedious for me.
もともと　ここに長くとどまる気などなかったしな
I was not going to stay here for a long time.
実はな　俺は今あるお方に仕えていて
The fact is that I now serve one person,
今から聖騎士団と名乗るルシタニア兵を倒しに行くところだ
and now we are going to destroy
lyusitaniantsev calling themselves the Knights of the Temple.
どうだ　お前も一緒に来ないか
What do you say, do not go with us?
お前ほどの腕があれば　心強い
For such a valiant warrior it will be a delight.
お前　今誰に仕えているのだ
You who are now serving?
Zabul Castle
ボダン率いる聖騎士団が立てこもるザーブル城は岩山の上にあった
Castle Zabul, who had occupied the temple knights Bodin,
located on top of a rocky mountain.
平地から直立する断崖を攻め入ることは不可能で
It was impossible to storm the cliffs that rise with the plain,
奇襲をかけることはできなかった
who were deprived of the possibility of a surprise attack.
ただし　ヒルメス軍は最初から持久戦に持ち込む気はなく
But the army of Hermes
and I did not intend to conduct a protracted battle.
They planned ruse to lure the enemy.
策を用いて　敵をおびき出すつもりであった
Damned! ..
おのれ　神旗を焼くとは　罰当たりの異教徒どもが
High Priest of faith Yaldabaoth, Bodin
They dared to burn the holy banner ?! Sinful Gentiles!
八つ裂きにしてくれよう
I will tear them to pieces!
とく神の異教徒どもを地獄にたたき込め
Send these scorners Gentiles to hell!
ははっ
There is!
ボダンめ　相変わらず　すぐに頭に血が上るとみえる
This Bodine ...
He's still the same hot-tempered as usual.
殿下の読みどおりでございましたね
Everything goes as you predicted, Prince.
クバード
Kuʙard.
で　これからどうする
Well? Now what?
左翼から俺の軍が攻める
My men will attack the left.
中央隊はザンデが率いる
Zande will lead our forces in the center.
そして　右翼は殿下の軍だ
And the right to attack the Prince of the army.
俺の出番は？
How do I attack?
お前は少しの間　見物していてくれ
And you, Tarry until our audience.
I would not mind Júcar at this time.
Note .: Júcar - beer.
その間　フカーが欲しいかな
久しぶりに腕が鳴るぜ
A supporter of Mr. Silver mask, Zande
I sense a hot battle, which have not been!
Do not hesitate! Behind me!
ひるむな　俺に続け
In the name of God Yaldabaoth!
イアルダボート神の名の下に
側面から
On the flank!
異教徒め
Damned heathens!
神の名において　貴様を断罪する
I bear to you the verdict in the name of God!
お前たちの神など知るか
I spit on your god!
神のおぼし召しを…
At the command of God!
ここで死ぬのは　お前自身のせいだ
You fall here through their own fault!
退避
Destroy them!
クバード
Kuʙard!
イアルダボート教に栄光あれ
Glory faith Yaldabaoth!
お前らこそ　くたばりやがれ
You yourself can taste the earth!
殿下
Prince!
お前には俺がパルスの王となり
You must survive, because later
玉座に着くところを見届けてもらわねばならぬ
I will witness my coronation in Pars.
それまで死ぬことは許さぬぞ　サーム
Until then, do not let die, Saam!
はっ
Yes!
ついに　ルシタニア軍はパルス人に敗れた
As a result, the army Lyusitanii
He was defeated by the Parsis.
聖騎士団は２０００を超す亡骸を戦場に残し　ザーブル城へと逃げ込んだ
temple Knights
They threw two thousand of their dead soldiers on the battlefield
and took refuge in the castle of Zabul.
二重の門扉を固く閉ざし　そびえ立つ岩山に身を潜めたのである
Securely closing the two gates,
They hid in the towering rocky mountain.
よくやってくれたな　クバード
You are well tried, Kubard.
Yes. But the castle had not yet fallen.
だが　城はまだ落ちちゃいないが
敵は持久戦に持ち込むつもりだろうが　こちらには策がある
The enemy appears poised to make a protracted battle,
but we have a plan.
A?
Follow the rules of propriety!
礼節を守らんか
このお方はパルスの国王となるヒルメス殿下だぞ
Before you prince Hermes, who will become the king of Parsa!
これはどうも　ヒルメス王子
Greetings, Prince Hermes.
サームから聞き及んではいたが　見事な働きであった
Saam told about you, but you and he proved himself.
あの城を落とし　ボダンを亡き者にする
We tear down the castle and run Bodin.
クバード　引き続き頼むぞ
Kubard, I rely on you.
ヒルメス王子　一つ　お聞かせ願えますか
Prince Hermes, allow something to ask you?
あなたが王位を求めるのは　いかなる理由ですか
For whatever reason you crave to get the throne?
Kuʙard!
クバード
お聞かせ願えますか
Do not answer me awarded?
貴様　分をわきまえろ
Oh you! Know your place!
All in order to bring in the kingdom of the world,
俺は王国に安寧をもたらすために　奪われた玉座を取り戻す
returning stolen my throne.
That's all.
それだけだ
奪われたのはルシタニアにですか　それとも…
Lyusitaniya stole it? Or...
いいかげんにしろ
Enough!
待て
Stay!
お前もいいかげんにせぬか
You also keep yourself in their hands.
Saam, I'm sorry, but I'll go.
サームよ　悪いが　俺は行くぞ
アトロパテネで敗れたおかげで　せっかく自由を手に入れた身だ
After the defeat at Atropatena I was now free to do whatever I want.
And I want to live a little longer.
もう少し　このままでいたいのでな
お前…
You...
好きにするがいい
As you want.
Reward him for his service today.
この男に此度の褒美を取らせよ
はい
Yes.
お前が言うとおり　ヒルメス王子が正統な血筋だというのなら…
If the prince Hermes really legitimate heir to the royal family, as you say ...
ルシタニアより国を取り戻したあと
When he will block the country have Lyusitanii,
We will have to wait for blood feud in the royal family Parsis
今度は玉座を巡って　パルス王家同士で血で血を洗う戦になるわけだ
in the battle for the throne.
Well...
それは…
そんな争いに巻き込まれるのはばかばかしい
And the foolish will be caught up in this ridiculous argument.
悪いな　俺のことは忘れてくれ
Sorry. Forget me.
ヒルメス王子にはお前が付いているのは分かった
Now I know that the prince Hermes have you.
では　アルスラーン王子には誰が付いているのだ
Then who is now serving Prince Arslan?
ダリューンとナルサスだ
Daryun and Narsus.
あの宮廷嫌いのナルサスがアルスラーン王子に付いているとはなぁ
Just think, a hater Narsus yard is Prince Arslan ...
面白い
Interesting.
それで　お前はこのまま　ヒルメス王子の幕営に身を置くつもりか
So? You're going to stay with the prince Hermes?
私はヒルメス殿下に忠誠を誓ったのだ
I swore allegiance to the prince Hermes.
Besides, if I'm not on his side,
それに　せめて私ぐらい付いてさしあげなくては不公平だろう
It will be unfair.
Although, it should be said that not much I can offer.
とはいえ　微力極まる身だが…
苦労しそうだな
Not easy to you.
だが　お前の武運は祈るとしよう
But I will pray for your success.
もっとも　俺は不信心者ゆえ　神々にはかえって逆効果かもしれぬがな
Mind you, I'm a believer,
so for me you can get the opposite effect from the gods.
じゃあな
Till.
fortress Peshavard
その年の３月
March of the same year,
アルスラーンは王太子の名において
as the Crown Prince Arslan
２つの歴史上重大な布告を発したのであった
published two historical order.
こちらがルシタニア追討令です
This is an order to search and destroy Lyusitanii.
故国を侵略したルシタニア人を追い払うために　全てのパルス人は
It calls on all parsiantsev gather in the fortress Peshavard
under the command of the Crown Prince Arslan,
王太子アルスラーンのもと　ペシャワール城に結集せよという檄文です
lyusitaniantsev to oust occupying our homeland.
そして　これが奴隷制度廃止令です
And it ordered the abolition of slavery.
According to him, when you ascend to the throne,
これは殿下が国王に即位した後
パルス国王は奴隷を全て解放し
King Parsis freeing all the slaves
人身売買を禁止することを明示しております
and prohibit the buying and selling of people.
ああ
Yes.
この布告が後に　この少年を
These laws subsequently lead Man
解放王アルスラーンと言わしめることになるのである
to the fact that it all will know how Arslan Liberator.
アルスラーン　１４歳と６か月
Arslan at the age of fourteen and a half years
still had to overcome many obstacles
彼の前には　まだいくつもの難関と
彼が知る由もない謎が立ちはだかっている
and know the secrets of which he does not know yet.
しかし　それらを克服したときこそ
But when he overcomes them all the same,
彼は　後世に名を伝えることになるのであろう
It will certainly take its place in history.
YakuSub Studio
kimi ga deatta kokoro wa kitto
All the souls that you could meet on the way,
translation Mu_Cool
hitotsu datte machigai janai
certainly it was pure and innocent,
Editorial Mu_Cool
onaji yume wo daite
We kept the same dream.
Making Weekend
michi wo tagaeta hito wo omotta
People walking different paths,
nozarashi no akogare wo kakagete susumu kouya
killed all my hopes and desires revive again.
hohoemi mo sono namida mo
Smile on his face, tears running down her cheeks,
koko ni suteteyukenai kara
If you want to go ahead, they should not be forgotten.
kage wo daite shiroku takaku
Covered by the shadow of the summer, so white and immense,
namonaki boku to kimi no hata
our with you nameless flag flies.
mada hatenaku tsudzuku kono mich ino kanata ni
There, on the road, which extends an endless path,
tatta hitotsu no hikari wo sen no kokoro ni
There is one bright light, and with it a thousand souls.
miageru sora wo shinjiteru
Believe in the sky above his head,
michibiku hoshi wo higashi no takami ni sashishimesu yo
there putevodnaâ our star in the east, ee do not engage.
yume wa kono te de kanaeru
And their cherished dream in flesh forces.
It Arlsan, Crown Prince of Parsis,
ここに今　パルスの王太子アルスラーンがよって
attempted to challenge the huge army Lyusitanii,
国土を侵略したルシタニアの大軍に戦いを挑もうとしているのだった
that gripped his country.
Next time: "The true face of the King."
次回　騎士の素顔
Chapter XX
And so the guy would be King.
少年は　そして王となる